<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Gihun Im</title>
<link>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://gihun-im.github.io/projects.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description>A personal academic website by Gihun Im</description>
<generator>quarto-1.6.40</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 05:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>LGBTQ+ Partner Loss</title>
  <dc:creator>Ongoing </dc:creator>
  <link>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/Spencer/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/Spencer/community.jpg" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Despite expanded access to higher education, sharp inequities remain in college completion rates, especially among lower-income students and students of color. National figures show that fewer than half of Hispanic and Black students, and under one-fifth of low-income students, earn a degree within six years. Institutional efforts to improve retention have made limited progress, often sidestepping the structural racism and classism embedded in academic systems that shape students’ daily realities.</p>
<p>Community-based organizations (CBOs) have stepped into this gap, developing College Success Programs (CSPs) that accompany students beyond admission. Grounded in community trust and culturally responsive approaches, these programs aim to sustain persistence and improve degree attainment. Early evidence points to their promise, yet systematic evaluation of how these programs operate and which elements most influence student outcomes remains scarce.</p>
<p>This mixed-method study seeks to address that absence. It will examine how CBO-led CSPs conceptualize, enact, and maintain college success among underrepresented students. The study will analyze which conditions CBOs identify as central to persistence, what specific supports they offer, how students experience those supports, and what measurable effects emerge in graduation data. The broader aim is to distill effective strategies that can inform institutional policy and guide both educational systems and community organizations in fostering equitable pathways to degree completion for students of color and those from lower-income families.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>CBO</category>
  <category>CSP</category>
  <guid>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/Spencer/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LGBTQ+ Educators in South Korea: A Photovoice Study</title>
  <dc:creator>Ongoing </dc:creator>
  <link>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/Photovoice/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="callout callout-style-simple callout-important callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
Award Alert!
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<p>This project was awarded the <strong>Lee Chang Kook Fund: Queer Research Grant</strong> by the Beyond the Rainbow Foundation in 2025.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/Photovoice/qtq.png" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="589"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>LGBTQ+ teachers often act as advocates and visible role models for LGBTQ+ students, yet they continue to face marginalization within heteronormative school systems. Many experience hostility rooted in identity-based stigma and must constantly balance their professional responsibilities with the concealment or negotiation of stigmatized aspects of themselves. Although existing research has emphasized these difficulties and called for institutional support, inclusive training, and safer school climates, most scholarship has emerged from Western, predominantly White contexts, limiting its cross-cultural applicability.</p>
<p>In South Korea, teaching is regarded as a respected and stable government profession deeply influenced by Confucian values, attracting many LGBTQ+ individuals seeking social legitimacy and financial security. Yet for queer teachers, this respectability often clashes with the silence surrounding LGBTQ+ identities in schools. The tension between public prestige and personal erasure remains poorly understood. Moreover, existing studies tend to frame LGBTQ+ teachers primarily as victims of oppression, paying less attention to their coping strategies, acts of resistance, and sources of community support. The predominant use of interview-based methods also constrains how deeply scholars can access the lived realities of these educators under systemic constraints.</p>
<p>To address these limitations, I will conduct a qualitative photovoice study with approximately 8 members of <a href="https://www.instagram.com/qtq_rainbow/">QTQ</a> (Queer Teachers with Queers) a peer support network for LGBTQ+ educators in South Korea. Photovoice, which integrates photography with narrative reflection, will allow participants to document their experiences and engage in group discussions that foster collective meaning-making. Using the PHOTO framework (<a href="https://psycnet.apa.org/doiLanding?doi=10.1037%2F1099-9809.10.3.302">Graziano, 2004</a><sup>1</sup>; <a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1300/J082v51n01_07">Hussey, 2006</a><sup>2</sup>), I will facilitate group interviews and, with consent, curate participants’ photographs on Padlet in collaboration with QTQ for public exhibition.</p>
<p>This study aims to generate culturally situated insights into the professional and personal lives of LGBTQ+ teachers in South Korea. By centering their agency and resilience, it seeks to move beyond deficit-oriented perspectives and highlight how these educators draw upon community networks and creative strategies to sustain themselves. The findings are expected to inform inclusive educational policy, teacher training, and institutional support systems. Ultimately, by amplifying teachers’ own voices, this research will contribute to a more nuanced understanding of both the struggles and strengths of LGBTQ+ educators working in non-Western school contexts.</p>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Graziano, K. (2004). Oppression and resiliency in a post-apartheid South Africa: Unheard voices of Black gay men and lesbians. <em>Cultural Diversity &amp; Ethinc Minority Psychology</em>, <em>10</em>(3), 302-316.↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Hussey, W. (2006). Silvers of the journey: The use of photovoice and storytelling to examine female to male transsexuals’ experience of health care access. <em>Journal of Homosexuality</em>, <em>51</em>(1), 129-158.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>LGBTQ+</category>
  <category>Photovoice</category>
  <guid>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/Photovoice/</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>CBI for Youth Resilience</title>
  <dc:creator>Ongoing </dc:creator>
  <link>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/CBI/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/CBI/youth.jpg" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img" width="800"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Resilience is a protective process that enables young people to adapt and grow in the face of adversity, supporting their healthy development and well-being. From a social-ecological perspective, resilience develops through interactions across multiple systems, including individual, relational, and structural levels, and requires coordinated efforts within and across these domains (<a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/13575270701733732">Brennan, 2007</a>)<sup>1</sup>. Community organizations are central to this process. By addressing systemic inequities and connecting public resources with those most affected, they help reduce disparities in access to care and promote fairer developmental outcomes for youth.</p>
<p>Although resilience has gained recognition as a key concept in youth development, community-based interventions remain underrepresented in the literature. Definitions and measurements of resilience also vary widely, making it difficult to compare findings across studies. To address these gaps, our study will conduct a scoping review of community-based programs designed to strengthen youth resilience. We are identifying relevant studies from PsycINFO and Scopus and will analyze them according to intervention type, outcome measures, and contextual factors influencing effectiveness.</p>
<p>The goal is to identify common components such as social support, interpersonal skill building, and empowerment that reflect central processes of resilience. The findings are expected to inform evidence-based frameworks and guide policy development for future community-based programs that promote youth resilience more equitably and effectively.</p>
<div class="callout callout-style-simple callout-note callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
Related Works
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<ul>
<li>Tang, Y., <strong>Im, G.</strong>, &amp; Zhang, Y. (2025, August 7-9). <em>Community efforts in promoting youth resilience: A scoping review of community-based programs</em> [Poster presentation]. APA 2025 Convention, Denver, CO, United States.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Brennan, M. A. (2007). Conceptualizing resiliency: An interactional perspective for community and youth development. <em>Child Care in Practice</em>, <em>14</em>(1), 55-64.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>Community-Based Intervention</category>
  <category>Resilience</category>
  <category>Youth</category>
  <guid>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/CBI/</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>LGBTQ+ Partner Loss</title>
  <dc:creator>Ongoing </dc:creator>
  <link>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/bereavement/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/bereavement/grief.jpg" class="img-fluid quarto-figure quarto-figure-center figure-img"></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>Since the 2015 legalization of same-sex marraige in the U.S., both social attitudes and legal structures have reshaped the landscape of LGBTQ+ partner loss. Building on <a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/pdf/10.1177/0269216316634601">Bristowe et al.’s (2016)</a><sup>1</sup> systematic review, we examined research on LGBTQ+ bereavement published after 2015.</p>
<p>We followed <a href="https://www.prisma-statement.org">PRISMA guidelines</a> and screened 1,656 studies from the Psychology Database and PubMed, ultimately including 10 qualitative studies. Through thematic analysis, we identified common bereavement reactions and LGBTQ+-specific experiences. The findings highlight the ongoing need for professional training and interventions that address the unique aspects of bereavement among LGBTQ+ people, even amid broader legal and social recognition.</p>
<p><span style="color: #FFD479;">We are currently preparing for submission based on the analyzed results.</span></p>
<div class="callout callout-style-simple callout-note callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
Related Works
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<ul>
<li>Kim, J., Kang, S., <strong>Im, G.</strong>, &amp; Kim, M. (2025, August 7-9). <em>A decade later: Revisiting LGBTQ+ partner loss and bereavement in the post-same-sex marriage era</em> [Poster presentation]. APA 2025 Convention, Denver, CO, United States.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Bristowe, K., Marshall, S., &amp; Harding, R. (2016). The bereavement experiences of lesbian, gay, bisexual and/or trans* people who have lost a partner: A systematic review, thematic synthesis and modelling of the literature. <em>Palliative Medicine</em>, <em>30</em>(8), 730-744.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>Bereavement</category>
  <category>LGBTQ+</category>
  <guid>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/bereavement/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Minority Stressors and Protective Factors of LGBTQ+ People During COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
  <dc:creator>Ongoing </dc:creator>
  <link>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/LGBTQ+_COVID-19/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="callout callout-style-simple callout-important callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
Award Alert!
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<p>This project was awarded the <strong>Mary Bywater Cross and Robert P. Newman Research Award</strong> by the University of Iowa College of Education in 2024.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>In May 2021, during the early stage of the COVID-19 pandemic in South Korea, a major news outlet publicly identified a patient as a “gay man” who had visited several gay clubs in Itaewon, revealing personal information without consent. The disclosure triggerd a surge of online hostility toward the LGBTQ+ community, deepening stigma and intensifying fears of infection among its members. Guided by the Minority Stress Model (<a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC2072932/">Meyer, 2003</a>)<sup>1</sup>, this project examines how <strong>minority stressors</strong>, such as the perceived threat of COVID-19, shape internalized stigma and, in turn, influence mental health outcomes among LGBTQ+ people. The project also explores whether <strong>protective factors</strong>, including community connectedness, buffer these adverse effects.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center" style="text-align: center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/LGBTQ+_COVID-19/dawoom.png" class="img-fluid figure-img" width="400"></p>
<figcaption>2021 Youth LGBTQ+ People’s Social Needs and Status Survey (Jeong et al., 2021)</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>I will use data from the <em>2021 Youth LGBTQ+ People’s Social Needs and Status Survey</em> (<a href="https://www.dawoom-t4c.org/397d4ebb-6ad4-4525-9b71-9706f13a5e8b">Jeong et al., 2021</a>)<sup>2</sup>, which includes responses from 3,911 LGBTQ+ people aged 19 to 34 in South Korea. For analysis, I will use SPSS 27.0, Mplus, and R to test the mediating effects of minority stressors and the moderating roles of protective factors in these relationships.</p>
<div class="callout callout-style-simple callout-note callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
Related Works
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<ul>
<li><strong>Im, G.</strong> (2024, July 19). <em>Relationships between perceived threat of COVID-19, internalized stigma, and depression among LGB people: Focusing on the moderating effects of community connectedness</em> [Paper presentation]. The 1st Conference of Junior Scholars Network of LGBTIQ Research, Seoul, South Korea.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Meyer, I. H. (2003). Prejudice, social stress, and mental health in lesbian, gay, and bisexual populations: Conceptual issues and research evidence. <em>Psychological Bulletin</em>, <em>129</em>(5), 674-697.↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Jeong, S., Kim, B., Shim, K., &amp; Han, S. (2021). <em>2021 youth LGBTQ+ people’s social needs and status survey</em>. Dawoom: Together for Change.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>COVID-19</category>
  <category>LGBTQ+</category>
  <category>Minority Stress</category>
  <guid>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/LGBTQ+_COVID-19/</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Relationship Between Decent Work and Decent Education</title>
  <dc:creator>Finished </dc:creator>
  <link>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/PWT_decentedu/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="callout callout-style-simple callout-important callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
Award Alert!
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<p>This project was awarded the <strong>Distinguished Student Research Award</strong> by Korea Employment Information Service in 2024.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center" style="text-align: center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/PWT_decentedu/decentedu.png" class="img-fluid figure-img" width="600"></p>
<figcaption>Decent education within PWT model (Duffy et al., 2022)</figcaption>
</figure>
</div>
<p>The recent expansion of the psychology of working theory (PWT; <a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0001879122000823">Duffy et al., 2022</a>)<sup>1</sup> introduces the concept of <strong>decent education</strong> to more fully explain how educational experiences influence career outcomes and overall well-being. Decent education encompasses not only formal schooling but also access to skill development, vocational training, and other learning opportunities that enable individuals to secure stable and meaningful employment. Within this framework, decent education functions as a foundation that equips people with the resources, knowledge, and competencies needed to navigate the labor market effectively.</p>
<p>In this study, we applied the expanded PWT model to young adults in South Korea to examine whether pathways to decent work differ by gender. Our analysis focused on whether work volition and career adaptability mediate the link between decent education and decent work. Data were drawn from the <em>Youth Panel Survey 2021</em> (<a href="https://survey.keis.or.kr/eng/yp/yp01.jsp">Hwang et al., 2021</a>)<sup>2</sup>, which included 3,403 Korean young adults employed in regular positions (정규직 in Korean). The sample comprised 1,901 women and 1,502 men, with a mean age of 25.32 years.</p>
<p><span style="color: #FFD479;">We are currently preparing for submission based on the analyzed results.</span></p>
<div class="callout callout-style-simple callout-note callout-titled">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-title-container flex-fill">
Related Works
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">
<ul>
<li>Bae, I., &amp; <strong>Im, G.</strong> (in progress). Relationship between decent education and decent work for youth: Mediating effects of work volition and career adaptability.</li>
<li>Bae, I., &amp; <strong>Im, G.</strong> (2024, June 5). <em>Relationship between decent education and decent work for youth: Mediating effects of work volition and career adaptability</em> [Paper presentation]. 2024 Employment Survey Conference, Seoul, South Korea.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>




<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Duffy, R. D., Kim, H. J., Perez, G., Prieto, C. G., Torgal, C., &amp; Kenny, M. E. (2022). Decent education as a precursor to decent work: An overview and construct conceptualization. <em>Journal of Vocational Behavior</em>, <em>138</em>, 103771.↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>Hwang, G., Gong, J., Cho, Y., Jung, K., &amp; Cho, C. (2021). <em>Youth Panel Survey 2021</em>. Korea Employment Information Service.↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>Career</category>
  <category>PWT</category>
  <guid>https://gihun-im.github.io/projects/PWT_decentedu/</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
